Guide to the Phillip Rhodes papers, 1957-2022 RL.01084
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Phillip Rhodes papers
1957-2022 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Rhodes, Phillip
RL.01084
67 Linear Feet
North Carolina born and raised composer, Duke alumnus, and composer-in-residence and professor at Carleton College. Collection comprises primarily scores, music sketches, recordings, professional files, and correspondence that follow the development of Rhodes' compositional career. Includes published compositions and unpublished student works for both vocal and instrumental ensembles, as well as concert programs, newspaper clippings, and other publicity related items from performances of his music.
Access Restrictions
Access note. Some materials in this collection are fragile audiovisual/photographic formats that may need to be reformatted before use. Contact Research Services for access.
Provenance
The Phillip Rhodes papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift from Phillip Rhodes from 2006-2023.
Biographical Note
Composer-in-Residence and Andrew W. Mellon Professor of the Humanities at Carleton College where he joined the faculty in 1974. Rhodes' principal teachers have been William Klenz, Iain Hamilton, Donald Martino, and Mel Powell. Born in Forest City, North Carolina in 1940, he received degrees from Duke University and the Yale University School of Music. Rhodes has been the recipient of numerous commissions and composition awards, including grants from the National Endowment for the Arts, the National Endowment for the Humanities, the Rockefeller Fund for Music, a citation and award from the American Academy of Arts and Letters, a Guggenheim Fellowship, two Tanglewood Orchestra Prizes, two McKnight Foundation Fellowships, two Fromm Foundation Commissions (Harvard), and a Bush Foundation Fellowship for Artists. Rhodes' compositions are published by C. F. Peters, E.M.I., Theodore Presser, J Ballerbach, and Schott, and recorded on labels including CRI, Centaur Records, First Edition (Louisville), Innova, New World Records, and Vienna Modern Masters.
Collection Overview
Collection comprises primarily scores, professional files, and correspondence that follow the development of Rhodes' compositional career. Name and Correspondence files consists mainly of correspondence between Rhodes and a variety of professional organizations, but also includes Rhodes' handwritten notes, some publicity materials, and other administrative documents. Personal Files includes unpublished works and music sketches from Rhodes' time as a student at both Duke and Yale, as well as some correspondence and biographical publicity materials more generally related to his career. Events and Programs consists of assorted concert programs from performances of Rhodes' music. Rhodes' music has been divided into four series based on genre: Chamber and Solo Instrumental Works, Choral and Solo Vocal Works, Operas and Oratorios, Orchestral and Wind Ensemble Works. The series include music sketches, drafts, revisions, original manuscripts, master sheets, piano reductions, published scores, conductor's scores, and when noted, instrumental parts.
Music -- Manuscripts; Composers -- United States; Composers -- United States -- Correspondence; Compact discs; Audiocassettes; Photographs; Opera -- 20th century; Chamber music -- 20th century; Music -- Scores; Choruses (Women's voices); Choruses (Mixed voices), Unaccompanied; Orchestral music -- 20th century; Carleton College. (Northfield, Minn.); Rhodes, Phillip
- Name and Correspondence Files, 1960-2016; undated; 1
  Scope and Contents
  Name and Correspondence files consists mainly of correspondence between Rhodes and a variety of professional organizations, institutions, performers, and other composers. Also includes Rhodes' handwritten notes, some publicity materials, and other administrative documents. Organizations include: American Composers Alliance, American Society of University Composers, BMI, Boston Opera, Bush Foundation, Carleton College, College Music Society, Contemporary Music Project, Duke University, C.F. Peters publishing, Ford Foundation, Kronos String Quartet, the Louisville Orchestra, the McLain Family Band, Minnesota Orchestra, National Endowment for the Arts, National Endowment for the Humanities, and the North Carolina Arts Council. Individuals include: Philip Brunelle, Joan Panetti, and Howard Richardson. Arranged alphbetically by folder title. Assorted correspondence arranged chronologically by decade.
  - Professional assorted correspondence, 1960-1989; 13 folders (Box 1)
    Phillip Rhodes' professional correspondence with a variety of organizations, institutions, and individuals affiliated with those organizations, including: the Louisville Orchestra, Minnesota Orchestra, Kronos String Quartet, C.F. Peters publishing, BMI, Carleton College, Berea College, Duke University, the MacLain Family Band, College Music Society, American Composers Alliance
  - Professional assorted correspondence, 1980-2001; 7 folders (Box 2)
  - Assorted contacts, 1970s-1980s (Box 43)
  - Letter "A", 1974-2012 (Box 43)
  - Paula Akbar, 1993-2014 (Box 43)
    National Symphony Orchestra member.
  - University of Alabama, 1979-1981 (Box 2)
    Correspondence
  - The American Composer Speaks, 1985-1986 (Box 2)
    "Some Thoughts on the Composer as Teacher" drafts and correspondence
  - American Composers Alliance, 1966-1998; 3 folders (Box 2)
    Correspondence, newsletters, meeting minutes, brochure
  - American Composers Orchestra, 1985-1986 (Box 2)
  - American Society of University Composers, 1968-1994; 4 folders (Box 2)
    Renamed Society of Composers. Includes correspondence, conference programs, form letters, administrative documents, newsletters, flyers, notes
  - Amherst College, 1968-1969; undated (Box 2)
    Correspondence, directory, notes, memos
  - Arizona State University Society of University Composers, 1985 (Box 3)
    Correspondence, conference programs
  - Associated Colleges of the Midwest Appalachian Project, 1976 (Box 3)
    Correspondence, notes, proposals
  - Letter "B", 1999-2015 (Box 43)
  - Banff Centre for the Arts, 1995 (Box 43)
    About Magic Pipe.
  - Barlow Commission, 1994 (Box 3)
    Application materials, correspondence, newsletters, flyer
  - Berea College, 1972-1973 (Box 3)
  - Bingham MacArthur Prize, 1974-1980 (Box 3)
  - BMI Backlog, 1975-1987; 2 folders (Box 3)
    Correspondence, memos
  - BMI, 1965-1979 (Box 3)
  - BMI Payments, 1972-1983 (Box 3)
    Receipts
  - Belwin Mills (Colombo) Publishing Co., 1968-1985 (Box 3)
    Royalty statements
  - Boston Chamber Ensemble, 1997-1998 (Box 3)
    Correspondence, flyer, article
  - Boston Opera, 1976-1977 (Box 3)
    Correspondence, report, notes, magazine, program
  - Brunelle, Philip, 1975-1977 (Box 3)
    Correspondence re: Minnesota Opera; includes programs
  - Bush Foundation, 1984-1985; 2 folders (Box 3)
    Correspondence, notes, reports, memos, receipts
  - Letter "C", 1978; 2000-2016 (Box 43)
  - Centaur Mountain View Recordings, 1995-2002 (Box 3)
    Correspondence, notes, proofs
  - C. F. Peters Publishing Co., 1966-1987; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - The Chicago Ensemble, 1980-1982 (Box 3)
    Correspondence, contracts, memos, newsletters, notes
  - Cincinnati Symphony, 1973-1978 (Box 3)
    Correspondence, memos, summer tour materials
  - University of Cincinnati, 1975 (Box 3)
    Correspondence re: job offer, campus visit
  - University of Cincinnati, Visiting Composer, 1989 (Box 3)
    Correspondence, notes, programs, flyer
  - College Music Society, 1993 (Box 3)
    Correspondence, programs newsletter
  - Columbia Pictures / Belwin Mills / Filmtrax, 1985-1990 (Box 3)
    Correspondence, royalty reports
  - The Composer in Performance Inc., 1972 (Box 3)
    Correspondence, flyer
  - Composers Commissioning Program Panel, 1987 (Box 3)
    Correspondence, application materials
  - Composer Recordings Inc. CD Project, 1996-1997 (Box 4)
    Correspondence, notes, flyer
  - Composer Recordings Inc. New Project, 1999-2000 (Box 4)
  - Composer Recordings Inc. Proofreading, 1997 (Box 4)
    Correspondence, drafts with edits
  - Composer Recordings Inc Carleton Recording, 1979-1980 (Box 4)
    Correspondence, catalog
  - Contemporary Music Project, 1969-1973; 5 folders (Box 4)
    Correspondence, memos, reports, notes, application materials, meeting minutes and agendas, conference program
  - Contemporary Music Project, Music Educators National Conference, 1966-1971; 2 folders (Box 4)
    Correspondence, memos, conference programs
  - Crane Festival, 1993 (Box 4)
    Potsdam, NY; Correspondence, programs, notes
  - Culbreath, Edward, 1970 (Box 4)
    Publicity materials
  - Letter "D", 1991-2015 (Box 43)
  - Edith Davis, 2000-2016 (Box 43)
  - Duke University, 1979-1982 (Box 4)
    Correspondence, reunion booklet
  - Letter "E", 2002-2011 (Box 43)
  - East Tennessee State University, 1995 (Box 4)
    Correspondence re: interview
  - Elmhurst College, 1968 (Box 4)
    Correspondence, proposal
  - Letter "F", 1995-2008 (Box 43)
  - Stephen Fisher, 1999-2013 (Box 43)
  - Flagstaff, AZ Symphony, 1982 (Box 4)
    Correspondence, notes
  - Florida State University, 1985 (Box 4)
    Correspondence, program
  - James Floyd, 2006 (Box 43)
  - Ford Foundation, 1985-1986; 2 folders (Box 4)
    Correspondence, notes, pamphlet, newspaper clippings, re: The Arts in Liberal Arts Colleges
  - Letter "G", 2000-2012 (Box 43)
  - Guggenheim Museum, 1979-1987; 2 folders (Box 4)
    Correspondence, brochures, notes, application materials, newspaper
  - Letter "H", 1994-2015 (Box 43)
  - Hattie Bishop Speed Music Room, 1972-1973 (Box 4)
    Correspondence, notes, memos
  - Letter "I", 1995-2015 (Box 43)
  - Illinois Music Educators Association, 1967 (Box 4)
    State meeting and conference documents
  - Illinois Summer Youth Music, 1967 (Box 4)
    Correspondence, programs, travel documents, memos
  - International Society for Contemporary Music, 1967 (Box 4)
    Correspondence, flyers, memos, programs
  - Letter "J", 2000-2011 (Box 43)
  - Jerome Foundation Opera Grant, 1982 (Box 4)
  - Rufus Jones, 2006 (Box 43)
  - Judith Finell Music Services, 1977-1978 (Box 4)
    Correspondence, notes, flyers
  - Letter "K", 1982-2014 (Box 43)
  - Kentucky Arts Commission, 1970-1974; 2 folders (Box 5)
    Correspondence, letters from schools, pamphlets, notes, memos, budget materials, programs
  - Kentucky Music Educators Association, 1969-1970 (Box 5)
    Correspondence, notes, photographs, program
  - Letter "L", 1988-2015 (Box 44)
  - Louisville, Jefferson County Youth Orchestra, 1970-1971 (Box 5)
    Correspondence, notes, program, budget memos
  - Louisville Project, 1969-1972; 3 folders (Box 5)
    Correspondence, notes, proposal drafts, article
  - Louisville Project, Composer in Residence, 1969-1974 (Box 10)
    Newspaper clippings, magazines, flyers, program
  - Louisville Project Alumni, 1982 (Box 5)
    Correspondence, notes, program re: alumni trip
  - Louisville Project Ballet, 1971 (Box 5)
    Correspondence, flyer, notes
  - Louisville Musical Projects Information, 1969; undated (Box 5)
    Correspondence, memos, notes, pamphlet
  - Louisville recording of "Following Picasso", 2012 (Box 44)
  - Lullaby project (Parma), 2015-2016 (Box 44)
  - Letter "M", 1992-2012 (Box 44)
  - Letter "Mc", 2001-2011 (Box 44)
  - Raymond McLain, 1988-2011 (Box 44)
  - McLain Family Band, Carleton College, 1980-1988; 2 folders (Box 5)
    Correspondence, programs, program notes, newspaper clippings, photographs, news release, speech draft
  - McKnight Fellowhsip, 1981-1988; 2 folders (Box 5)
    Correspondence, summary report, application materials
  - McKnight Panel, 1985 (Box 5)
  - Music Educators National Conference, 1984 (Box 5)
  - Millikin University, 1975 (Box 5)
    Correspondence, flyer re: guest composer
  - Minneapolis Chamber Symphony, 1981-1982 (Box 5)
    Correspondence, notes, program
  - Minnesota Arts Board Fellowship, 1978-1980 (Box 5)
    Correspondence, booklets
  - Minnesota Composers Forum, 1982 (Box 5)
    Correspondence, memos, agenda re: Lyman conference
  - Minnesota Orchestra, 1975-1976 (Box 5)
    Correspondence, program, newspaper clippings
  - Minnesota State Arts Board, Grant Acceptance, 1979-1980 (Box 5)
  - Mount Union College, 1979-1980 (Box 5)
  - Music copying rates, 2014-2015 (Box 44)
  - Letter "N", 1994-2011 (Box 44)
  - National Association of Schools of Music, 1974-1975 (Box 5)
    Correspondence, program, notes
  - National Endowment for the Arts, 1974-1984; 3 folders (Box 5)
    Correspondence, application materials, financial reports, receipts, ledger
  - National Endowment for the Arts Folk / Ethnic Pilot Application, 1977 (Box 5)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities, 1978-1984; 2 folders (Box 5)
    Correspondence, application materials, drafts, notes
  - National Endowment for the Humanities Panel, 1985 (Box 5)
    Correspondence, notes, program, booklet
  - Maria Niederberger, 2009-2014 (Box 44)
  - North Carolina Arts Council, 1979 (Box 5)
    Correspondence, articles, newspaper clippings
  - North Carolina Forum, 1984-1986 (Box 5)
    Correspondence, program, lecture outline
  - Letter "O", 1979-2010 (Box 44)
  - Sunny Oh, 2009-2013 (Box 44)
  - Opera stuff, 1987-1988 (Box 44)
  - Orion Recordings, 1977-1981 (Box 6)
  - Cornelia Orth, 2009 (Box 44)
  - Letter "P", 2008-2016 (Box 44)
  - Panetti, Joan, 1966-1970; 2 folders (Box 6)
    Correspondence, program, publicity materials
  - Perspectives of New Music, 1990-1993; 3 folders, 1 audiocassette (Box 6, 12, Audio-cassette RL01084-CS-0001)
    Correspondence, notes, music sketches, published score re: Festschrift contribution for Donald Martino
  - Promotion, 2003-2007 (Box 44)
  - Letter "R", 2001-2011 (Box 44)
  - Jane Carol Bowness Rhodes, circa 2023 (Box 44)
    Biographical information about Janes Rhodes.
  - Richardson, Howard, 1974-1977 (Box 6)
    Correspondance re: Broadway project
  - Letter "S", 1991-2015 (Box 45)
  - San Francisco Chamber Players, 1977 (Box 6)
    Correspoindence, program, flyers
  - Sheldon Soffer Management, 1974-1976 (Box 6)
    Correspondence, notes, brochures
  - Sigma Alpha Iota, 1972 (Box 6)
    Correspondence, notes, program, article
  - Southeastern Composers League, 1964-1968; 2 folders (Box 6)
    Correspondence, memos, flyers, newsletters, meeting minutes, conference programs
  - Southern Methodist University, 1973-1980; 2 folders (Box 6)
    Correspondence, programs, newsletter
  - Nane Spainhour, 2009 (Box 45)
    ETSU contract.
  - St. Paul Chamber Orchestra, 1975 (Box 6)
    Correspondence, newspaper clippings
  - Sugar Mountain Music Camp, 1972-1973 (Box 6)
    Correspondence, brochure, newspaper clipping
  - Letter "T", 1982-2009 (Box 45)
  - Tango Fantasy, 2015-2016 (Box 45)
  - Texas A&M University, 1992 (Box 6)
    Correspondence re: tenure review for Peter Lieuwen
  - Dan Trueman, 1990-2007 (Box 45)
  - Letter "U", 1970 (Box 45)
  - Letter "V", 1996-2009; 2015 (Box 45)
  - Vienna Modern Masters CD Project, 1998-1999 (Box 6)
    Correspondence, contracts, permissions, credits
  - Letter "W", 1982-2014 (Box 45)
  - Wells, William B. / Third Angle, Commission, 1993-1994 (Box 6)
  - Wesleyan College, West Virginia Commission, 1982 (Box 6)
    Correspondence, programs, program notes
  - Western Kentucky University Choral Music Symposium, 1990 (Box 6)
    Correspondence, flyers, schedule, notes, scores, biographical profiles
  - Western Michigan University, 1969-1970 (Box 6)
  - WNIB / WNIZ Classical 97, 1994 (Box 6)
    Chicago, IL; Correspondence
  - Letters "X-Y", 1970-2009 (Box 45)
  - Yale University, 1966-1971 (Box 6)
    Correspondence re: teacher placement
  - Letter "Z", 1969-1981 (Box 45)
- Personal Files, 1964-2006; undated; 3
  Personal Files includes unpublished works and music sketches from Rhodes' time as a student at both Duke and Yale, as well as some correspondence and biographical publicity materials more generally related to his career. Student works include brass choir arrangements for Duke Univeristy Chapel services and unfinished sketches for larger ensembles. Other materials include job application letters, correspondence with assorted publishers, official performance notices, and biographical materials that include newspaper clippings and documentation of Rhodes' professional activities. Grouped and arranged by material type.
  - Brass choir arrangements for Duke University Chapel services, 1961-1962 (Box 6)
    Music sketches, scores, notes
  - Large notebook, 1962-1966 (Box 6)
    Music sketches, early and student works
  - Music sketches and manuscript copies of early works, 1958-1960; 3 folders (Box 6)
  - Student composition exercises, 1961-1962 (Box 6)
  - Fugue in C minor, 1965 (Box 6)
    Manuscript copy
  - Unfinished music sketches, 1965 (Box 6)
  - Early attempt at a band piece, 1957-1958 (Box 41)
    Music sketches
  - Three unfinished large ensemble works, 1962-1967 (Box 41)
    Music sketches; also includes orchestration assignment from Duke University of Sergei Prokofiev's Op. 12, no. 1
  - Assorted notes, 1971 (Box 7)
  - Job application letters, 1967-1974 (Box 7)
  - Letters to publishers, 1969 (Box 7)
  - Professional activities and performances, 1966-1972 (Box 7)
    Biographical profiles, resumes, lists of performances, reviews, programs
  - Promotional materials, 1972 (Box 7)
    Biographical profiles, newsletter
  - Recordings of Phillip Rhodes' music, 1977-1978; undated; 2 folders (Box 7)
    Correspondence, publicity and cover art materials
  - Official performance notices, 1980-1989 (Box 7)
  - Assorted newspaper clippings, 1962-1970; undated (Box 10)
  - No Strings Attached, Music By Phillip Rhodes, 2006 (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0011)
  - Phillip Rhodes: With a Mountain View, 2002 (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0047)
  - Phillip Rhodes: memory, Art, time, Form, 1997 (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0055)
  - In Performance at Carleton, The Music of Phillip Rhodes, 2004 (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0045)
  - Music sketches and notes, 1961-2002 (Box 45)
  - Photographs of Rhodes by Thomas Hardin, 1971 (Box 48)
    Taken in Louisville.
- Events and Programs, 1960-2005; 4
  Events and Programs consists of assorted concert programs from performances of Rhodes' music from, beginning with his time as a student at Duke University. Also includes documents from his visit to Duke in 1984, with programs, lecture notes, and correspondence with Robert Ward. Arranged chronologically by decade.
  - Concert programs, reviews, and newspaper clippings, 1960-2005; 11 folders (Box 7)
    Assorted performances of Phillip Rhodes' compositions
  - Duke University Visit, 1984 (Box 7)
    Correspondence with Robert Ward, programs, leture notes
- Chamber and Solo Instrumental Works, 1961-2022; undated; 5
  Chamber and Solo Instrumental Works comprises music Rhodes wrote for instrumental chamber ensemble or solo instrument. Some works, such as Autumn Setting and Visions of Remembrance, include one or two vocal soloists within the ensemble. Some works include correspondence, program notes, newspaper clippings, and other publicity materials related to their performance. Most of the pieces include recordings, music sketches, full scores, original manuscripts, proofs, master sheets, and when applicable, complete parts. A few of the pieces also include Rhodes' personal copy with markings. Arranged alphabetically by title of piece.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Access note. Some materials in this series are fragile audiovisual/photographic formats that may need to be reformatted before use. Contact Research Services for access.
  - Appalachian Breakdown for solo piano, 2006-2008; 1
    - Music sketches, drafts, full score, 2006-2008 (Box 8)
    - Melville's Dozen, with Nicola Melville, pianist, 2008 (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0012)
  - Autumn Setting for soprano and string quartet, 1968-1990; 2
    - Portland State performance, 1990 (Box 8)
      Correspondence, programs, notes
    - Tanglewood Festival of Contemporary Music Commission, 1968-1970; 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Music sketches, full score and complete parts, 1969 (Box 13)
    - Quartet of the University of Chicago Contemporary Chamber Players; Elsa Charleston, soprano, 1970 April 10 (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0044)
    - Correspondence, 1969-1971 (Box 8)
    - Music sketches, original manuscript copy, full score, 1968 (Box 14)
    - Paul Zukofsky, violin; Robert Sylvesterm, cello, 1999 (Box 12, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0070)
    - Edition Peters score, 1973 (Box 45)
  - Dargason, 2009
    - Draft and notes, 2009 July (Box 45)
      Irish fiddle tune.
  - Duo for violin and piano, 1965-1968; 4
    - Jenny Halfmann, violin; Joan Panetti, piano, 1966 May 10 (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0036)
    - Paul Zukofsky, violin; Gilbert Kalish, piano, 1968 (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0035)
    - Music sketches and full scores, 1965-1966 (Box 34)
  - Duo for violin and violoncello, 1973
    - Edition Peters score, 1973 (Box 45)
  - Ensemble Etudes, 1967; 5
    - Music sketches and full scores, 1967 (Box 34)
    - University of Illinois Summer Music Program, 1967 July (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0037)
  - The Face I Carry With Me for soprano, flute, viola, cello, and piano, 1982-1985; 6
    - Program, notes, proofs, 1982-1985 (Box 8)
    - Music sketches, 1982 (Box 30)
    - Full revised scores, 1985 (Box 30)
      Includes Phillip Rhodes' copy with markings
    - Revised full score original manuscript, 1985 (Box 30)
    - Revised 1985 (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0048)
    - Score and notes, 1982-1985 (Box 48)
  - Fanfare and Reflections on the Carleton College Alma Matter for brass choir and percussion, 2002; 7
    - Full score, 2002 (Box 33)
  - Fiddletunes for solo violin and synthesized strings, 1994-2022; 8
    - Correspondence, program notes, magazine clipping, 1997 (Box 8)
    - Memphis State Festival, 1994 (Box 8)
      Correspondence, notes, programs
    - Portland Festival, 1999 (Box 8)
    - Winona State University New Music Festival, 1998 (Box 8)
    - Music sketches, full scores, program notes, 1994-1997 (Box 33)
    - Performance tape of synthesized string parts; includes instructions for performance, undated (Box 12, Cigar-box RL01084-DAT-0001)
    - Draft score, 2021-2022 (Box 45)
    - Violin part, 2021-2022 (Box 45)
    - Full score, 2021-2022 (Box 45)
  - Following Picasso: A Fantasy after Stravinsky, 2010
    - Working notes, 2010 January - July (Box 48)
    - Manuscript final copy of score, 2010 (Box 48)
    - First draft of final printed version, 2010 July (Box 48)
    - Event program, 2010 September (Box 48)
  - An Inaugural Processional for trumpet and organ, 1987-2002; 9
    - Music sketches, 1987 (Box 34)
    - Full score and complete parts, proofs, 1987 (Box 8)
    - Original score and master sheets, edited copy, 1987-2002 (Box 8)
      Includes program and newspaper clipping
  - Meditation Upon Lactantius' De Ave Phoenice for bassoon and harp, 2002-2003; 10
    - Correspondence, 2002-2003 (Box 8)
    - Music sketches and full score, 2002-2003 (Box 8)
  - Museum Pieces for clarinet and string quartet, 1973-2000; 11
    - Bakersfield, CA performance, 2000 (Box 8)
      Correspondence, program notes
    - Music sketches, full score, proofs, 1973 (Box 31)
    - Carleton College, Latin-American Music Festival, 1991 April 12 (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0022)
    - St. Paul Chamber Orchestra, undated (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0021)
    - Carleton College event program, 1991 (Box 45)
    - Organ arrangement, 1993 (Box 48)
  - Partita for solo viola, 1978-1986; undated; 12
    - Recording by Ann Woodward, 1980-1982 (Box 8)
      Correspondence, notes, scores, publicity materials
    - Music sketches, full score, master sheets, 1978 (Box 35)